Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1675-1960; 27 boxes, 8.5 linear feet
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, July 26, 1815; 10x7-34; Hill, Hannah Sellers
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.with P.S.by Samuel Sellers. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Philadelphia, Aug. 1, 1815; 10x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Long Branch, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. E. Bend, Philadelphia, Aug. 4, 1815; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    Long Branch, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. Refers to Dr.Wistar.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Long Branch, Aug. 6, Aug. 8, 1815; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, New York, Aug. 17, 1815; 12x7-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. On same sheet is letter from Sophonisba Sellers to Mrs. E. Bend; [Aug.17,1815]
  - Letter to Mrs. E. Bend, Aug. 17, 1815; 12x7-1/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. On same sheet as Coleman Sellers to S.Sellers; Aug.17,1815.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 28, 1815; 10x8; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Money difficulties. Refers to Coleman and Sophonisba Sellers.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 2, 1815; 10x8; Bradford, R. B. (Royal Bird), 1844-1914
    New York, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Linneaus Peale, Trenton, Sept. 10, 1815; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Charles L[innaeus] Peale, Trneton, Sept. 24, 1815; 10x8; Summers, Andrew, 1795-1843
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 67
  - Letter to Linnaeus Peale, Trenton, Oct. 18, 1815; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Family news. Enclosed originally in letter from A. Summers to Linnaeus Peale; Oct.19,1815.
  - Letter to Linnaeus Peale, Trenton, Oct. 19, 1815; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Summers, Andrew, 1795-1843
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Enc. Friendly letter. For enclosure, see: Rubens Peale to C.L.Peale; Oct. 18, 1815. vol VI p.68
  - Letter to Charles L[innaeus] Peale, Trenton, Nov. 16, 1815; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Summers, Andrew, 1795-1843
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 69
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], 1815; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785 (Box 3)
    Long Branch, 27th, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning their father's health. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Charles] Linnaeus Peale, Feb. 20, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827 (Box 4)
    Bellefield, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Advice for married life. Concerning the museum. For duplicate, see Letterbook,XIV,12.
  - Letter to Mrs. Eliza [Burd Patterson] Peale, Philadelphia, Feb.21, 1816; 10x8; Peale, Elizabeth De Peyster Coalman(?)
    Wilmington, A.L.S. 2p.and add., end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, April 11, 1816; 10x8; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.with P.S.by Rubens Peale to C.W.Peale. Concerning the settlement of the estate of William De Peyster.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, April 17, 1816; 10x7-3/4; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Business of the estate of William De Peyster.
  - Letter to [Charles] Linnaeus Peale, Trenton, April 21, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.with P.S.by Rubens Peale. Paternal advice. Concerning the museum. For duplicate, see Letterbooks,XIV,32.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Upper Darby, July 23, 1816; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 14, 1816; 10-1/4x8; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Remsen's designs on William De Peysters estate.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Upper Darby, Aug. 16, 1816; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [C.W.] Peale, Aug. 17, 1816; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Sophonisba [Peale Sellers], Sept. 26, 1816; 10x8-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. Describes Boston.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Oct. 29, 1816; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Remsen, Henry, 1762-1843
    New York, A.L.S. 6p.and add. Business of estates due them.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Nov. 14, 1816; 10-1/4x8; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Sale of shells. Business with Remsen. Refers to Mitchill.
  - Letter to [C.W. Peale], Dec. 24, 1816; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. 2 copies Original of C.1 in Massachusetts Historical Society; of C.2 in University of Texas.
  - Letter to [Charles Willson] Peale, Philadelphia, March 6, 1817; 9-1/2x8; New-York Historical Society
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Pintard. 2p.and add. Asks for minerals and fossils. vol VIp.71
  - Letter to C.W. Peale, March 16, 1817; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Original in University of Texas. Bur. of rolls, v.6,368 - Ser.2,v.68,170.
  - Invitation from Elizabeth Poole and John Sellers, jr., March 30, 1817; 4-3/4x4-3/4; Poole, Elizabeth
    to Hannah Sellers [Hill] D. 1p. vol I p.91
  - Invitation from Elizabeth Poole and John Sellers, jr. to George Hill, March, 1817; 4-3/4x4-3/4; Poole, Elizabeth
    D. 1p. vol I p. 90
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, May 14, 1817; 10x8; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
  - Invitation to Samuel Sellers to view an exhibition at the school house, May 28, 1817; 5x8; Albertson, B.
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: B.Albertson and 4 others. 1p.and add. vol I p.91
  - Letter to Charles W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, June 3, 1817; 10x7-3/4; Norris, John
    Wellsborough, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning land speculation. Refers to the museum. vol VII p. 9
  - Letter to Ann or Hannah Sellers, Upper Darby, June 14, 1817; 5x8; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. On same sheet is B.Albertson. Invitation...; May 28, 1817.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin Peale, Baltimore, June 17, 1817; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning the settlement of William De Peyster's estate.
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, Philadelphia, July 23, 1817; 9x7-1/4; Hill, Peter, -1857
    Chester, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Plans to visit, but would like to postpone the visit a few days if possible.
  - Letter to Angelica Peale, Aug. 10, 11, 1817; 8" x 10"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Domestic affairs. Dreadful flood.
  - Letter to Angelica Peale, Aug. 14, 1817; 8" x 10"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Domestic affairs. The flood.
  - Letter to [C.W.] Peale, Feb. 18, 1818; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 17, 1817; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale family papers.) Concerning business for the museum.
  - Letter to R[ubens] Peale, Museum, Feb. 19, 1818; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Delaplaine, Joseph, 1777-1824
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection. ) Asks for Mr. Otis to paint Portrait of C.W.Peale for his collection.
  - Letter to Ann or Hannah Sellers, Mill Bank, May 8, 1818; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. Concerning Rubens Peale.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 2, 1818; 10x8; Teely, Elizabeth
    Carlisle, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. vol VI p.73
  - Letter to Charles W[illson] Peale, Sept. 22, 1818; 10x8; Thornton, William, 1759-1828
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Friendly. Concerning teeth. Refers to Monroe. vol VI p. 74
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Oct. 6, 1818; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Teely, Elizabeth
    Carlisle, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. vol VI p.75
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1818; 10x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    A.L.S. 2P.and add. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 76
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Nov. 9, 1818; 9-3/4x8; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Dec. 4, 1818; 9-3/4x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 78
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay Peale], Philadelphia, Dec. 14, 1818; 9-3/4x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Concerning Mr. Lukens. vol VI p. 79
  - Letter to Titian Ramsay Peale, Dec. 21, 1818; Unidentified
  - Letter to Nathan Sellers, Darby, Feb. 18, 1819; 7-1/2x6; Wilson, John, 1768-1835
    Lower Merion, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. vol I p.93
  - Letter to [Charles Willson] Peale, Philadelphia, March 14, 1819; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Beeker, Augustus
    Leipzig, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. In German. Typed translation. Forwards natural history objects and wishes to exchange them for American objects. vol VI p.83
  - Letter to Titian Peale, March 20, 1819; 8-1/4x7; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, L. 2p. Copy. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Paternal advice for conduct in life. Bound in with: Life of C. W. Peale (see Series 7, Volumes)
  - Letter to Mrs. N[athan] Sellers, Philadelphia, March 21, 1819; 13x8; Ashbridge, Mary Kenyon
    Chillicothe, ohio, A.L.S 3p.and add. Friendly letter vol I p92
  - Letter to Titian [Peale], March 26, 1819; 8-1/4x7; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    L. 3p. Copied by Anna Peale. (see Peale papers. Mills collections Gives advice for his travels. Bound in with: Life of C. W. Peale (See Series 7, Volumes).
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Pittsburgh, April 5, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale family papers.) Family news.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, St. Louis, April 6, 1819; 10x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Pittsburgh, April 7, 1819; 10x8; Simes, Jane Ramsay Peale, 1785-
    Philadelphia, L.S.: Jane Ramsay Peale, Sarah Miriam Peale and Anna Claypoole Peale. 4p., add.,end. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 85
  - Letter to Mr. Clay, April 28, 1819; 8" x 3 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Pop[lar] For[est], A.N.S. with initials. 1p. and add. Instruction in writing deeds. Presented by Charles Coleman Sellers, July 1946.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, St. Louis, May 1, [1819]; 10x8; Peale, Sarah Miriam, 1800-1885
    Philadelphia, L.S.: 3p.with P.S.by Anna C. Peale. 4p.,add. Family news.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, St. Louis, May 10, 1819; 13-1/4x8; Peale, Charles Linnaeus, 1794-1832
    Bellefield, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. Family news. Refers to draisiana.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, St. Louis, July 14, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end.with P.S.by Elizabeth De Peyster Peale [Patterson]. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, Aug. 4, 1819; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale family papers.) News of family and friends.
  - Letter to [C.W.] Peale, Aug. 7, 1819; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Poplar Forrest, near Lynchburg, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Original in University of Texas. 2 Copies
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Mill Bank, Aug. 17, Aug. 18, 1819; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Samuel, 1780-1850
    Long Branch, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Charles W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 30, 1819; 10x8; Levering, A. R.
    Georgetown, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the rice bunting. Refers to Wilson.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, Oct. 27, 1819; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale family papers.) News of family and friends. Business of the museum.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Council Bluffs, Nov. 7, 1819; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Sarah Miriam, 1800-1885
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. News of home. Family news.
  - Letter to Nathan Sellers, Darby, Dec. 24, 1819; 7-3/4x6; Wilson, John, 1768-1835
    Lower Merion, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. Refers to grandson of Israel Pemberton.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 24, 1820; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Wilson, John, 1768-1835
    Lower Merion, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning Robert Owen's plans for the poor in Great Britain.
  - Letter to Franklin [Peale], Feb. 2, 1820; 8" x 10"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. The Borie trail. Has resumed his experiments. Mentions Franklin's electrical machine.
  - Letter to Titian Peale, Council Bluffs, Mo., Feb. 21, 1820; 8" x 9 3/4"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, A.L.S. 6p. and add.
  - Letter to "Dear Cousin" [Eliza Burd Patterson Peale], March 11, 1820; 10" x 8"; Yeates, Casper
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 2p. In re her marriage to Mr. [Rubens] Peale.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, March 15, 1820; 10x8; De Peyster, John, 1765-1846/9
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, March 20, 1820; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Peale family papers.) Friendly, family letter. Concerning his marriage to Eliza Patterson. Museum business.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, March 29, 1820; 10x7-3/4; Patterson, Elizabeth De Peyster Peale, 1802-1857
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.: "politeness of Major Long", end. Family news. vol VIp.91
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, St. Louis, April 8, 1820; 9x7-3/4; Peale, Sarah Miriam, 1800-1885
    Baltimore, A.L.S.with initials. 4p.,add.,end. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. Christiana [Runyon] Peale, April 11, 1820; 13x8-1/4; Peale, Charles Linnaeus, 1794-1832
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Franklin is in an accident. Refers to Tilghman.
  - Letter to [C.W. Peale], April 22, 1820; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Original in University of Texas. 2 Copies
  - Letter to Franklin [Peale], May 12, 1820; 8" x 10"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Borie trial. Desires casts from Mr. Sully.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, May 22, 1820; 10x8; De Peyster, John, 1765-1846/9
  - Letter to Charles W[illson] Peale, Baltimore, June 3, 1820; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale family papers.) Concerning the museum and changes which must be made. Family news.
  - Letter to Raphaelle [sic] Peale, Annapolis, June 25, 1820; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Concerning paints on a pallette. For duplicate, see Letterbooks,XVI,177.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, July 7, 1820; 10x8; De Peyster, John, 1765-1846/9
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add. end. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, July 17, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Remsen, Henry, 1762-1843
    Philadelphia, New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers [Hill], Long Branch, July 19, 1820; 10x8; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Quincy Adams], July 21, 1820; 10x8; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning a patent.
  - Letter to [William] Thornton, July 21, 1820; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. Nn.and Dd. Sellers. 1p.and end. Copy. Concerning a patent.
  - Letter to Nathan Sellers, July 29, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Thornton, William, 1759-1828
    L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning a patent.
  - Letter to [John Quincy Adams], July 29, 1820; 10x8, 1x5-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.L.S. 2p.and end. Concerning a patent.
  - Letter to William Thornton, Washington, Aug. 1, 1820; 10x8; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Copy. Concerning a patent.
  - Letter to Franklin [Peale], Aug. 28, 1820; 8" x 10"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Has finished his large picture. Family affairs.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1820; 8x6-1/4; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Oct. 3, 1820; 9-3/4x8; Remsen, Henry, 1762-1843
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to Charles W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1820; 9-1/2x7-1/2; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l D. Ingraham, Harrisburg, Nov. 24, 1820; 10x8; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    Upper Darby, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Draft. Asks favor for a poor man who did not fight in 1814.
  - Letter to the Philadelphia select council, Dec. 25, 1820; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, A.L.S. 2p.and add: George Vaux, end. Concerning the rent for the museum.
  - Letter to the Common council of the city of Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1820; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. and add. From original in possession of Haverford college. Related to his Museum.
  - Letter to [C.W.] Peale, Dec. 28, 1820; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Original in University of Texas. 2 Copies.
  - Letter to Nathan Sellers, Mill Bank, 1820?; 13-1/2x8-1/4; Sellers, John, 1762-
    [ca.]. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the grist mill.
  - Letter to R[ubens] Peale, Philadelphia, Jan. 6, 1821; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Ricord, Alexander
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning taxidermy. volVII p.14
  - Letter to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Jan. 10, 1821; 9-3/4x8; Lederer, Lewis
    New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Will exchange natural history objects for Vienna collection. vol VII p.15
  - Letter to [John Sellers?], Jan. 24, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Poole, William, 1764-1829
    A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letters. vol I.p. 97
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Jan., 1821; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. Refers to Major Long. vol VI p.95
  - Letter to John Sellers, Upper Darby, Feb. 10, 1821; 10x8; Poole, William, 1764-1829
    B[randy]Wine, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. vol.I p. 97
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, Feb. 28, 1821; 10-1/4x8; Ploss, Henry
    Leipzig, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Copy. Will exchange birds. vol VII p. 16
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, March 11, 1821; 10x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    [received] A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end.: Mr. Sully. Friendly letter. vol VI p. 97
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Christiana [Runyon Peale], Belfield, March 22, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Charles Linnaeus, 1794-1832
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, March 23, 1821; 9x7-1/4; Milnor, James, 1773-1845
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning eskimos. Vol VIIp.18
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, March 26, [1821]; 10x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. vol VII p.19
  - Letter to [Charles Willson?] Peale, Philadelphia, April 13, 1821; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Higbee, Thisbee G.
    Raleigh, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the sale of a museum.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, Philadelphia, April 18, 1821; 10x8; James, Edgar
    Smithland, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Sent him a paper on geology. Refers to Major Long.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, April 25, 1821; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Perkins, A. R.
    Burlington, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end.and end. (mentioning C.W.Peale). Will exchange red fox for admission to museum. vol VII p. 24
  - Letter to [Charles Willson Peale], June 2, 1821; 8x5; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Wants the museum. Family troubles.
  - Letter to [Rubens] Peale, June 4, 1821; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Harper, Joseph L.
    Dover, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Will donate chicken to his museum. vol VII p. 26
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, June 11, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Perkins, A. R.
    Burlington, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends skin of white rat. vol VII p.24
  - Letter to [Rubens] Peale, Philadelphia, June 11, 1821; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Shepherd, Abraham
    Ripley, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Makes donation to museum. vol VII p. 27
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, June 13, 1821; 10x8; Taylor, Israel, 1782-1850
    Trenton, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Donates bird to museum. vol VII p.28
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Baltimore, June 14, 1821; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Belfield, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning the museum and finances. Copy in Letterbooks, XVII, 44.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Baltimore, June 21, 1821; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. vol VII p.29
  - Letter to [Rubens] Peale, Philadelphia, June 25, 1821; 10x8; Escher, Heinrich, 1789-1870
    Zurich, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Copy. Concerning the exchange of insects. vol VII p.30
  - Letter to the Trustees of Peale's museum, July 4, 1821; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hewitt, William
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Deposits cannon of von Tromp's in the museum. vol VII p.31
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Baltimore, July 6, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.,end.and add. (see Peale family papers.) Family news. Concerning natural history. Refers to Long, Say and Ord.
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Baltimore, July 15, 1821; 10x8; Peale, Charles Linnaeus, 1794-1832
  - Letter to Titian [Ramsay] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 4, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Refers to J.Vaughan and Z.Collins.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s W[illson] Peale, Philadelphia, Aug. 18, 1821; 9-1/2x7-1/2; De Peyster, Philip, 1771-1846
    New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Business of disputed estate.
  - Letter to [Rubens] Peale, Oct. 25, 1821; 10x7-3/4; Benclay, Joseph (Box 4)
    Baltimore, A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add.,end. Will sell his moose skin. vol VII p. 34
  - Letter to R[obert ?] Gilmor, jr., Jan. 5, 1822; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860 (Box 5)
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Note to [Mrs.] Hannah [Sellers] Hill, Jan. 14, [1822]; 6-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, John
    A.N.S.: J.& E[lizabeth Poole] Sellers. 1p.and add. Reports the birth of a son.
  - Letter to Samuel [Sellers], Jan. 15, 1822; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, 1781-1834
    Richmond, A.L.S. 2p. Business of fire engines. Refers to the university of Virginia.
  - Letter to Lehman, Harrisburg, Jan. 23, 1822; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Concerning canals.
  - Letter to Titian R[amsay] Peale, Philadelphia, March 18, 1822; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Lee, William
    L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning payment while on trip with Long. vol VII p. 36
  - Letter to Joseph Heister, March 23, 1822; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Nathan, 1751-1830
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Recommends James Willcox for judgeship.
  - Letter to his brother [Benjamin Franklin Peale?], May 8, 1822; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and end. (see Peale, Rubens. Letters to Franklin Peale...) Concerning money matters.
  - Letter to his brother [Benjamin Franklin Peale ?], June 11, 1822; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Baltimore A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale, Rubens. Letters to Franklin Peale...) Concerning the museum. Family news.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin [Peale], June 25, 1822; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865